杰森:站住!!!
Jason: Freeze!!!
麦琪:杰森,你干什么呢?
Maggie: Jason, what are you doing?
杰森:我吗?麦琪,你到底在干什么?早上5点半,我还以为来窃贼了呢?
Jason: Me!??Maggie what are you doing up!?It's 5:30 in the morning, I thought I heard a burglar.
麦琪:于是你抓了个衣服架???你想这样去抓贼吗?把他挂在上面?
Maggie: So you grabbed a coat rack???What were you going to do?Take his rack?
杰森:真有贼就这样对付他.这是我奶奶拿手的茴香面包吗?
Jason: If it came to that.Is that my famous grandma's dill bread?
麦琪:是啊,是今晚要吃的.它必须要发酵14个小时呢.
Maggie: Yes, it's for dinner tonight, it has to rise for 14 hours you know.
杰森:我知道今晚这顿饭很重要.
Jason: I know this dinner is a big deal Maggie.
但至于要5点半起床张罗吗?
But who in the right mind gets up at 5:30?
迈克:大家早上好!嘿,你们正忙着呢.
Mike: Good morning everybody!Hey this works in here.
杰森:迈克,你来干什么?
Jason: Mike what are you doing up?
迈克:今天我不上课.
Mike: Well, I'm not teaching class today.
杰森:现在才5点半.
Jason: It's 5:30
迈克:是吗?
Mike: It is?
麦琪:你今天很兴奋.
Maggie: And your chipper.
迈克:是吗?
Mike: I am?
麦琪:你还吹口哨来着.
Maggie: You were whistling
迈克:吹了吗?哦,我得坐一坐了.这都是卢克给闹的.
Mike: I was?Aww man I got to sit down, this is all Luke's fault.
麦琪:谁是卢克.
Maggie: Who's Luke?
迈克:他是我的一个学生,
Mike: He's one of my students, that little weasel.
简直是个小滑头.光他一个人就把我的头搞大了.
I mean it was bad enough when it was just him,
现在每个人都在效仿他.
now he's got everybody doing it.
麦琪:上课讲话,调皮捣蛋?
Maggie: Talking back, cutting up.
迈克:不!他是个优等生.
Mike: No!Getting A's
杰森:不领你情的讨厌鬼.
Jason: Ungrateful little maggot.
迈克:不,不,爸爸,我是认真的.我班上的优等生增加了一倍.
Mike: No no, Dad I'm serious the number of A students in my class have doubled.
麦琪:一倍??
Maggie: Doubled!!??
迈克:是的,现在两个了.
Mike: Yeah, now I got 2
麦琪:迈克,你太了不起了.
Maggie: Mike, that's great!
迈克:不,妈妈,
Mike: No it's not mom, look at me,
这没什么.想想吧,
I mean I use to be able to sleep in until noon,
以前我可以一觉睡到中午,天气好的话可以到下午三点.
on a good day till three.
现在,我刚躺下就要起床了,还吹着口哨.
Now I'm getting up when I use to go to bed.And I'm whistling.
麦琪:嗨,迈克,别忘了请凯特吃晚饭的事.
Maggie: Hey Mike, about the dinner with Kate...
迈克:喔,喔,对了,
Mike: Oh Oh, yeah mom listen thanks for going through so much trouble,
妈妈,谢谢你费心思张罗.你明白凯特对我很重要.
you know how special Kate is to me.
麦琪:我当然明白.今晚6点半开始,好吗?
Maggie: I know, I'll expect you at 6:30?
迈克:好的!等等,
Mike: Right!Wait, wait a minute, that's tonight!?
是今天晚上吗?我怎么计划今天晚上去上课呢?
What was I thinking scheduling it on a school night?
哦,这可怎么办啊!??
Oh no what's happening to me!??
杰森:这是迈克第一次请凯特来家吃晚饭,看看你都准备了些什么?
Jason: So mike has invited Kate here for dinner for the first time and
有…哦!!
you are preparing what?Let us see...The...OH!!
10磅重的烤排骨,黑胡椒晚餐酱汁,
The ten pound rib roast, the black peppercorn dinner's sauce,
10恺撒什锦色拉,还有花了14个小时做出来的奶奶拿手的茴香面包.
the caesar salad, and my grandmother's 14 hour dill bread.
你不喜欢凯特,是吗?
You don't like Kate do you?
麦琪:你怎么这么说呢?
Maggie: Why would you say a thing like that?
杰森:因为你把我妈妈做给你的饭菜原样照搬出来了.
Jason: Because that's exactly the meal my mother use to make for you.
麦琪:但我并没有任何让你妈妈感到害怕的地方.
Maggie: Your mother never had anything to fear from me.
我不是一个四处招摇,演技很烂的时尚模特,
I wasn't a glamorous fashion model slash actress that was about to lead
可以把你领到阔佬圈子里,而那是你没办法适应的.
you into a jet set world you couldn't possibly be ready for.
杰森:阔佬圈子?
Jason: Jet set world!?
麦琪,
Maggie, so far Kate's biggest modeling assignment has been the cover of
凯特至今最成功的一次模特经历就是在一家种子杂志上当了一回封面女郎.
a seed catalogue.
麦琪:但在我看来,
Maggie: Well if you ask me,
她手拿干草叉的样子似乎太招摇了.
she looked a little to comfortable holding that pitch fork.
杰森:将来她没准就是我们的儿媳妇了.
Jason: It could end up as our daughter in law,
我不过是想让你们一开始就能建立良好的关系罢了.
I just want to make sure you two get this relationship off on the right foot.
麦琪:杰森,我早上4点半就爬起来张罗让人头疼的这顿晚饭了.
Maggie: Jason, I got up at 4 stinking 30 in the morning and I'm cooking
如果这也不算高姿态的话,
this stinking feast, if that doesn't say
那我不知道该怎么办才好了.
lovin from the oven, then I don't know what does.
开萝尔:早上好!
Carol: Good morning!
麦琪:早上好!
Maggie: Good Morning!
杰森:开萝尔,你怎么又回家住了?
Jason: Carol, what are you doing home again?
你该住在学校宿舍的.
You're supposed to be living at the dorm.
开萝尔:我跟室友布兰又闹翻了.
Carol: I had another fight with my roommate Bran.
杰森:为了什么?
Jason: About what?
开萝尔:她老把门锁上不让我进去.嗨,
Carol: About whether she unlocked the door and let me in.
为什么做老奶奶茴香面包啊?
Hey what's with great grandma's dill bread?
麦琪:凯特要来吃晚饭.
Maggie: Kate's coming to dinner.
开萝尔:我以为你不喜欢她呢?
Carol: I thought you liked her?
本:谁要来吃晚饭?
Ben: Who's coming to dinner?
开萝尔:凯特.
Carol: Kate.
本:哦,太棒了!她能在我的种子杂志上签字吗?
Ben: Oh great!Do you think she will autography my seed catalogue?
杰森:本,凯特是你哥哥的女朋友.
Jason: Ben, Kate happens to be your brother's girlfriend.
本:我知道.可她还是个模特呢.
Ben: I know that,
模特都有什么样的朋友啊?天啊,
but she's also a model and what kind of friends do models have?Babes.
也许她可以给我介绍两个朋友,而朋友又会介绍另两个朋友,
Maybe she'll introduce me to two friends and then they'll introduce me
如此这般地介绍,朋友的朋友的朋友.
to two friends and so on and so on and so on.
迈克:泰德斯科先生,你不必陪我一起来储藏室的,
Mike: Mr.Tedesco you didn't have to walk me to the store room,
只要给我钥匙就可以了.
you could've just given me the keys.
泰德斯科先生:废话,只有我知道这钥匙的密码.
Mr.Tedesco: Nonsense, only I understand the key coding system.
迈克:蓝钥匙配蓝锁,对吗?
Mike: Blue key, blue lock right?
泰德斯科先生:别跟任何人透露一个字.
Mr.Tedesco: Don't breathe a word of this to anyone.
迈克:呃,走之前,你能告诉我布告栏在哪里吗?
Mike: Uh, listen before you go, can you tell me where the bulletin boards are?
泰德斯科先生:我也不知道.自从剃掉大胡子后,
Mr.Tedesco: I have no idea,
我就再没进去过.
I haven't been in there since I shaved off my Fumanchu.
也许我不该跟你说这些的.
Perhaps I shouldn't have shared that with you.
记得离开时把门锁好.
Be sure to lock up when you leave.
对了,楼里有只流浪猫到处乱跑,
There's a stray cat roaming around the building ,
搞的我寝食难安,非得抓住它.
I will not rest until I catch it.
迈克:你没试着叫它猫咪猫咪吗?
Mike: Did you try here kitty kitty?
泰德斯科先生:别以为我给你开了门,我们就是哥们了.
Mr.Tedesco: Just because I opened up with you, it doesn't mean were friends.
迈克:在上课之前,我想说一下新的布告栏上有两张得了"A"的试卷.
Mike: Before we begin,
I'd just like to point out that we have a new bulletin board with two "
A" papers on it.
卢克 布鲁沃尔.很明显他今天很忙没来上课;另外一个是乔斯努奈兹.
Luke Brower, who is apparently too busy to be with us this morning and Jose Nunez.
乔斯:要是妈妈能出来看到这个就好了.
Jose: If only ma were paroled to see this.
迈克:啊…布鲁沃尔先生.
Mike: Ah...Mr.Brower.
卢克:抱歉,我迟到了,西沃老师.
Luke: Sorry I'm late Mr.Seaver.
迈克:卢克,你连续迟到三次了.
Mike: That's the third time in a row Luke,
也许我该打555电话让他们早上叫醒你.
maybe I should call 555-Deli and leave a wake up call?
卢克:别担心,我只在课堂上睡觉.
Luke: Don't worry I only sleep in class.
迈克:好吧,好吧.
Mike: Alright alright.Now, these are emergency notification cards,
这些都是紧急事故通知卡,办公室需要知道出了事故我们该找谁.
the office needs to know who to call incase of an accident.
乔斯:找泰娅费利普斯好吗?如果做口对口急救的话,我乐意奉陪.
Jose: How about Tyra Phillips, hey if I am going to get mouth to mouth, I want to enjoy it.
迈克:好了,别闹了.把卡片填好后交上来.
Mike: Alright alright.Just fill them out and pass them back.
同学们,这一周,
Ok people, this week I was asked to do some remedial work in French,
我要求给你们补习法语课.我补好了,现在我要教给你们.
so I did it and now I am going to teach it to you.
现在我们想一个短语,然后翻译成法语.
Now let's think of a phrase we would like to translate into French.
卢克:西沃老师,门口有个漂亮女士.
Luke: Mr.Seaver, there is a beautiful woman at the door.
迈克:很好,好极了.西沃在英语和发育里是一样的.所以我们先从西沃老师开始吧.
Mike: Good, perfect, now Seaver is the same in both languages, so we'll start with Mr.Seaver.
卢克:不是,门口真地有一位漂亮女士.
Luke: No no no, there really is a beautiful woman at the door.
全班:喔!!!
Class: WOO!!!
迈克:好了!好了!你们互相交流一会吧.嗨,凯特,我正在上课呢.
Mike: OK!OK!Just parlez vous among yourselves.Hey Kate I'm in the middle of a class.
凯特:我知道.事情不紧急,我也不能来打扰你.
Kate: I know.I wouldn't bother you unless it was very urgent.
迈克:好!好!什么事?
Mike: Ok!Ok!What is it?
凯特:我穿哪件衣服去你家吃晚饭啊?
Kate: Which one of these should I wear to your house for dinner tonight?
迈克:你中断了我的讲课只是来问我穿哪件愚蠢的衣服吗!!?
Mike: You're interrupting my class to talk to me about a dumb dress!!?
凯特:这有什么愚蠢的.我想让你们全家都喜欢我,特别是你妈妈.
Kate: This isn't dumb.I want your family to like me especially your mother.
迈克:我妈妈非常喜欢你.
Mike: My mother does like you.
凯特:不可能.她大学毕业,
Kate: She can't.She's a college graduate,
是一个事业有成的母亲.
a successful career woman and a mother.
在她看来,我不过是个末流学校的辍学生,后来当上了演技很烂的模特.
To her I'm just a girl that dropped out of junior college to be a model slash actress.
迈克:哦!演技很烂的模特!!?
Mike: Oh!Model slash Actress!!??
凯特!!真是难以想象这是从我妈妈嘴里说出来的话.
Kate!I couldn't even imagine those words coming out of my mother's mouth.
振作些,别担心,一起都会好的.有我呢,一切都会顺利.
I mean come on, stop worrying everything's going to be fine, I'm going to be there to make sure everything is ok.
凯特:那好吧,你说我穿哪件?
Kate: Ok, just tell me which one.
迈克:好的.
Mike: Ok.
凯特:这件!?
Kate: This one!?
迈克:呃,呃…
Mike: Uh huh...
凯特:那这件!?
Kate: Or this one!?
迈克:这一件.
Mike: This one.
迈克:呃,泰德斯科先生,你找我吗?我们开门见山好吗?今晚我家有个重要的聚会.
Mike: Uhh, Mr.Tedesco, you sent for me?Listen can we make this kind of quick because I've got a big family dinner to go to tonight.
泰德斯科先生:西沃,我们整个制度面临崩溃的危险.
Mr.Tedesco: Seaver our entire system is on the verge of collapse.
迈克:发生什么了?
Mike: What happened?
泰德斯科先生:我们丢了一张紧急事故通知卡.
Mr.Tedesco: There is an emergency notification card missing from this stack.
迈克:哦,不会吧!至于这么大惊小怪吗?
Mike: Oh no!Should we use the code of silence?
泰德斯科先生:混乱的恶魔正在门口徘徊,你还这么漫不经心.
Mr.Tedesco: The wolf of anarchy is at our door and you're feeding him kibble.
花名册上有15个名字,可卡片只有14张.卢克 布鲁沃尔的卡不见了.
There are 15 names on the roster and 14 cards.Brower, Luke is cardless.
迈克:我有个好主意.
Mike: I got a crazy idea,
你觉得明天让他再填一张好不好?
what do you say I have him fill one out tomorrow?
泰德斯科先生:不可能.教育条例第9,4,3,破折号,6条款有明确规定.
Mr.Tedesco: Impossible, directive nine, four, three dash six clearly states any distributee in the educational matrix.
迈克:泰德斯科先生,我们可以睁一只眼,闭一只眼吗?
Mike: Mr.Tedesco can we just cut to the chase?
泰德斯科先生:5点之前必须把卡交上来,否则他拍屁股走人.
Mr.Tedesco: I get his card by five or he's out on his undocumented keister.
迈克:他是我最好的学生.我希望他留下来.
Mike: He's one of my best students, I need his keister right where it is.
泰德斯科先生:不要这么粗鲁.我很抱歉,可9,4,
Mr.Tedesco: You needn't be crude.
3,破折号,6条款有明确规定.
I'm sorry directive nine, four, three dash six clearly states.
迈克:我知道,放松点.
Mike: I know, just relax, I got an idea.
有主意了.好的,那个555的电话.
Ok, what was that number five five five, deli.
泰德斯科先生:西沃老师,只有我有权打这个电话.
Mr.Tedesco: Mr.Seaver only I am authorized to use that phone.
迈克:喂,熟食店吗?
Mike: Hello, So ho Pete's?This is Francis X.
我是佛兰西斯泰德斯科.请找一下你们的一个雇员,叫卢克布鲁沃尔.
Tedesco and I need to speak with one of your employees Luke Brower.
他是个伙计,也许是个干杂活的.你肯定?好的,
I think he's a waiter, well maybe a bus boy.You sure?Ok thank you.
谢谢你.真怪,他们没听说过他.
That's funny they never heard of him.
泰德斯科先生:我们也是.我曾想调阅他的档案,却没找到.
Mr.Tedesco: Neither have we, I just tried to pull his file, there isn't one.
迈克:档案丢了吗?
Mike: His file is missing?
泰德斯科先生:不是,卢克布鲁沃尔根本不存在.
Mr.Tedesco: No, Luke Brower does not exist.
迈克:他当然存在,就在我的班上.他是我最好的学生.
Mike: Well of course he does, he's in my class.He's one of my best students.
我在布告栏上贴上了他得A的卷子.呃,
I have an "A" paper of his on my bulletin board.Uhhh, Mr.
泰德斯科先生,我能借用一下你的钥匙吗?
Tedesco can I borrow your keys?
泰德斯科先生:西沃,你清醒一下吧.
Mr.Tedesco: Seaver you're delirious.
迈克:呃,嗨,你看!!你要抓的猫在那里!!
Mike: Uhh.Hey look!!There's that cat you're after!!
泰德斯科先生:在哪里!!??
Mr.Tedesco: Where!!??
迈克:那里!!我堵住走廊,你去叫帮手.
Mike: There!!I'll seal off the hallway you call for backup!
泰德斯科先生:动物管理处吗?
Mr.Tedesco: Animal regulation?This is Francis X.
我是佛兰西斯泰德斯科.
Tedesco, we finally had a positive sighting on that cat I've been complaining
我们终于发现我一直抱怨的那只猫了.
about.
快拿捕猫用的夹子和网兜过来,追捕开始了.
Grab your cat nip, man your nets, the hunts afoot.
我要让那只破猫彻底消失.
That means get your raggedy keister down here right now.
迈克:卢克!
Mike: Luke!
卢克:呃,西沃老师.我在找一本新的法语书.我那本早过时了.
Luke: Umm, Mr.Seaver, I'm looking for a new French book.
我来找找,就是这本,我可以学习了.
I've got an outdated one.Let's see, here's the right book, now I can learn.
迈克:等等,先别管书了.呃,你先给我解释这张床是怎么回事吧.
Mike: No no, never mind the book ,uh why don't you go ahead and explain this bed to me?
卢克:呜!!肯定有人睡在这里!!
Luke: Aww!!Someone must be sleeping in here!!
迈克:你一定会告诉是谁.
Mike: I bet you can tell me who.
卢克:好吧,我说.我需要个地方混几个晚上.我跟家人闹翻了.
Luke: Ok I needed a place to crash for a couple of nights.I had a fight with my folks.
迈克:这样啊,我明白了.
Mike: Well Josh, I know how that goes, I mean my folks...
你和家人…嘿,等等,只是几个晚上吗!??
hey wait, a couple of nights!?
卢克,你有灯,书本,还有有线!
Luke look you got a lamp, you got books, you got cable!
卢克:我趁打特价的时候买的.
Luke: I took advantage of the false subscription special.
迈克:别编了.好了,
Mike: No no, Hey hey!
好了,你还是把来龙去脉告诉我吧.
Hey come on now, why don't you tell me what's going on here!?
卢克:我一丁点也不告诉你!!
Luke: I don't have to tell you anything!!
迈克:你一定会的.我是你老师啊.
Mike: Sure you do!I'm your teacher.
卢克:哼!也不看看你是怎么上的课,连一个法语单词都不懂.
Luke: Huh!You should see yourself teach French you don't know one word of it.
迈克:你说什么??车库,饭店,还有啦啦.
Mike: Oh Oh Yeah!??Garage, Restaurant, ooh la la.Hey there's five.
嘿,我说了5个单词呢.等一下,我为什么要提自己辩解呢?你很好.
Wait a minute, why am I defending myself?You're good.
卢克:谢谢.
Luke: Thanks.
迈克:你没有地方住,是吗?
Mike: You don't have any place to live do you?
卢克:我当然有了.
Luke: Sure I do.
迈克:那好吧.
Mike: Oh ok!Fine fine,
好,好,
then why don't you just go ahead and fill out your address here and this
那你为什么不把你的家庭地址填到这张紧急通知卡上呢.
emergency notification card.
卢克:哦,我不会出现什么紧急情况的.
Luke: Oh I'm not planning on having any emergencies.
迈克:我们可能会出现,到时候需要找到你啊.
Mike: We might and we need to get a hold of you.
卢克:我担心因此会收到许多垃圾邮件.
Luke: I hope this doesn't mean I get any junk mail.
迈克:西48街728号?
Mike: Seven twenty eight, west forty eight?
卢克:我家就在那里.
Luke: That's my house.
迈克:真的?这地址可是在河里啊.
Mike: Really?This address is in the middle of the river.
卢克:我家在船上.你还真不赖.
Luke: House-boat.You're good too.
迈克:谢谢.卢克,我不信你在那里住.
Mike: Thank you.Luke I can't believe you're living here.
卢克:是吗,就在那里啊.
Luke: Well, I am.
迈克:你把我整糊涂了.你爸妈呢??
Mike: Well I don't get it, what about your parents!??
卢克:我没有,也不需要什么爸妈.我在这里很好.
Luke: I don't have any and I don't need them.I am doing fine right here.
迈克:卢克,就没有比这更好的地方了吗!!??
Mike: Luke, there's got to be some place better than this!!??
卢克:是啊,是啊,还有哪里?
Luke: Yeah Yeah, Like where?
迈克:还有,还有,比方说城市郊区的某个舒适的地方.
Mike: Like Like, some sort of city outreach happy sort of place!!??
卢克:我都去过了.还是这里好.
Luke: I've tried all the happy places, this is better.
迈克:不,不可能的,
Mike: No, this can't be Luke, I mean this is New York,
卢克,这里是纽约,是充满了兄弟情谊的城市啊.
this is the city filled with brotherly love.
卢克:那是费城吧.
Luke: That's Philadelphia.
迈克:哦,但是卢克,在这样一个风之城里.
Mike: Oh, but Luke in a city like this the windy city.
卢克:芝加哥.
Luke: Chicago.
迈克:是吗,我是想说,你总要找个体面点的地方.
Mike: Well my point is that you are entitled to a decent place to live
我知道一个地方了.跟我来,去那个希望之城.
and I know just how to get you one.Follow me.The city of hope.
卢克:那是医院.
Luke: Hospital.
卢克:哦,不,不,泰德斯科会把我转到儿童福利院的.
Luke: Aww No no no, Tedesco is just going to turn me over to the Bureau of Child Welfare.
迈克:不,不会的.坐下,听我说,我保证那是一个好地方.
Mike: No No No, sit you can listen and I promise that is the one
place we will not call
泰德斯科先生:你们动物管理处的人连一只猫都抓不住.
Mr.Tedesco: You animal regulation people do nothing but pussy foot.
那只猫就在楼里到处闲逛,眼睛像灯笼,
That cat is prowling in this building with his jackal lantern eyes and
舌头像砂纸.一定要把它抓住.
his sand paper tongue.And I want him stopped!!!
迈克:泰德斯科先生,我找着它了!
Mike: Mr.Tedesco, I found him!
泰德斯科先生:哈利路亚,在哪里?在走廊里吗?
Mr.Tedesco: Hallelujah, where was he?Out in the hall?
迈克:不,在储藏室里.
Mike: No, in the store room.
泰德斯科先生:它在啃一只死耗子吗?
Mr.Tedesco: Gnawing on a dead mouse I presume?
迈克:不,不是.但他饿了,而且他还无家可归.
Mike: No no, but he was hungry, I mean I'm sure he doesn't have a home.
泰德斯科先生:哦,你在胡说什么!怎么会呢?
Mr.Tedesco: Well, Boohoohoo!He can't stay here.
迈克:喂,你能注意一下你的措辞吗?他就在走廊外边呢.
Mike: Listen, can you just watch what you say, he's right outside the hall.
泰德斯科先生:哦,抱歉.
Mr.Tedesco: Oh forgive me,
我没有伤害他脆弱心灵的意思.
I wouldn't want to injure his oh so tender feelings.
迈克:我觉得他很担心将要发生在自己身上的事.
Mike: I think he is quite worried about what might happen to him.
泰德斯科先生:我可以让他幼小的心灵有个好归宿.他们会开一辆卡车过来,
Mr.Tedesco: Well let me put his little mind to rest.
把他带到城里,然后扔进笼子里.
They'll send a truck for you, run you downtown and throw you in a cage.
迈克:听起来很太残忍了,你不觉得的吗?
Mike: That sounds kind of harsh don't you think?
我还是希望有人会收留他.
I was kind of hoping that maybe he could be adopted.
泰德斯科先生:如果他幼小而且伶俐还有可能.可他太大了.
Mr.Tedesco: Well maybe if he was young and cute.
人们只能收留他两个星期,
His age they'll keep him for two weeks,
没人要的话,就会让他永远睡过去的.
if no one wants him they'll put him to sleep.
迈克:你说的话太让人恶心了!
Mike: That's the sickest thin I've ever heard!
泰德斯科先生:不算什么.在过去,
Mr.Tedesco: Nothing.In the old days,
人们会用粗棒子打死他,然后扒了皮做吉他.
they'd club it with a blunt object and cut him up for guitar strings.
迈克:我们在谈一个15岁的孩子呢!!
Mike: We are talking about a 15 year old boy here!!
泰德斯科先生:西沃,你晕了吧.我们在谈一只猫!
Mr.Tedesco: Stay with me Seaver, we're talking about a cat!
迈克:我们在谈卢克布鲁沃尔.他一直住在储藏室里!
Mike: We're talking about Luke Brower, he's been living in the storeroom!
泰德斯科先生:猫是他的!!??
Mr.Tedesco: And the cat is his!!??
迈克:别提那只猫了!!!这里住着一个无家可归的孩子!!!
Mike: Would you forget about the cat!!!We have a homeless boy living here!!!
泰德斯科先生:什么!!??这是学校.
Mr.Tedesco: What!!??This is a school, we can't have kids here!!!
孩子怎么能住这里!!!我要叫儿童福利院的人过来.
I'll call the bureau of child welfare.
迈克:不,不要这样.我向他保证不这样的.
Mike: No no no, I promised him we would do something else.
泰德斯科先生:没别的办法.
Mr.Tedesco: There is nothing else.
麦琪:迈克呢?
Maggie: Where is Mike?
杰森:迈克到底在哪里 !?
Jason: Where the devil is Mike!?
凯特:迈克究竟在哪里!?
Kate: Where the heck is Mike!?
克莉丝:我饿坏了!迈克呢?
Chrissy: I'm hungry!Where's Mike!?
本:要是凯特认识漂亮小妞该多好啊.
Ben: I wonder if Kate knows any teenage babes?
杰森:哈哈,真想不到凯特你和麦琪穿一样的衣服.
Jason: Ha ha Imagine that, Kate you and Maggie both having the same dress.
麦琪:真的,我还没注意到呢.
Maggie: Really, I hadn't noticed.
杰森:尽管尺寸有区别…这没什么关系…呃…迈克跑哪去了?
Jason: Well their probably different sizes though... Not that that matters...
uh... Where the hell is Mike?
麦琪:我觉得咱们等的够长的了.
Maggie: Well I think we've waited long enough.
凯特,我们知道迈克很在乎你,所以有机会邀请你来和西沃一家共进晚餐,我们十分高兴.
Kate, we know ho much Mike thinks of you so we're glad for this opportunity to welcome you to a real Seaver family dinner.
凯特:别这样.我得谢谢你,西-麦琪-西沃太太.
Kate: Why thank you Mrs.Sea-Maggie---Seaver.
麦琪:请你尝尝一片杰森奶奶拿手的极品茴香面包吧.
Maggie: May I offer you a slice of Jason's grandmother's famous blue ribbon
dill bread?
凯特:面包里有发酵粉吗?
Kate: Does this bread have yeast in it?
麦琪:是的,松软吗?
Maggie: Yes, isn't it fluffy?
凯特:哦,抱歉,我不吃有发酵粉的食物.
Kate: Oh I'm sorry, I'm afraid I don't eat anything with yeast.
杰森:我喜欢吃.我吃一片,谁还要?
Jason: Well I do, so I will and then we'll pass it to....
麦琪:怎么了,你对发酵粉过敏吗?
Maggie: What's the matter are you allergic to yeast?
凯特:不是的.吃了它就会感觉浑身不舒服.
Kate: No no, It's just that it can throw your whole system out of whack.
本:最近我一直在考虑不吃发酵粉了.
Ben: You know lately I've been thinking of giving up yeast.
你有漂亮朋友可以给我引见吗?
Would your beautiful friends give me some pointers?
麦琪:我们就是,宝贝…
Maggie: Here you go sweetheart..
克莉丝:我不想浑身难受!
Chrissy: I don't want to get whacky!
麦琪:克莉丝,你奶奶天天吃这种面包,一直吃了95年呢.
Maggie: Now Chrissy, your grandmother ate this bread everyday of her life for 95 years
克莉丝:后来呢?
Chrissy: Why'd she stop?
麦琪:后来她死了.
Maggie: Well she died.
克莉丝:我不吃.
Chrissy: Pass.
杰森:嘿,迈克回来了.那是迈克.
Jason: Hey, there he is, there's Mike.
麦琪:太好了.我去拿主菜.
Maggie: Wonderful, I'll get the main course.
每个人:嗷!!
Everyone: Awwww!!
克莉丝:那是开萝尔.
Chrissy: It's only Carol.
开萝尔:我被赶出宿舍了.跟你们一样,我很不痛快.太过分了.
Carol: I got driven out of my dorm room.
哦,你好,凯特.
I don't like it any better than you guys do, deal with it.Oh, hi Kate.
凯特:嗨.
Kate: Hi.
开萝尔:迈克呢?
Carol: So where's Mike?
凯特:呃,他来晚了,太晚了.
Kate: Umm he's late, very very late.
开萝尔:这么没什么.没有他,
Carol: Well that's alright, we'll have a lovely time without him.
我们一样会很开心.要是现在我起身走开,他们就不会这么上心了.
I wonder if anyone will notice if I get up and leave right now.
麦琪:菜来了.这是加了各种佐料的烤牛肉.
Maggie: Well here it is, roast beef with all the fixings.
开萝尔,你怎么来了?
Carol what are you doing here?
开萝尔:妈妈,我是你女儿,
Carol: Mom, I'm your daughter, we love each other,
我们是亲骨肉.你们大家都烦我吗!!??
will you people get off my back!!??
麦琪:凯特,吃第一块能带来好运气.
Maggie: They say the first slice is lucky.
凯特:呃…迈克没说我在节食吗?
Kate: Umm...Didn't mike mention my diet to you?
麦琪:节食??
Maggie: Diet??
杰森:哦,你这么漂亮的姑娘还需要减肥吗?
Jason: Now, why would an attractive young woman like yourself need to
听我的,吃一块.
lose weight?I say come on, eat up.
凯特:哦,不,
Kate: No no no, it's not a weight loss diet.
不,我不是在减肥,这只是一种生活方式.
It's more of a way of life.
麦琪:你是素食者吗??
Maggie: You're a vegetarian??
凯特:不,不是的.我只是不吃有头有脸的东西.
Kate: No no, not exactly I just don't eat anything with a face.
我也知道烤牛肉很美味,但一想到曾经是一头牛,
I'm sure the roast beef is wonderful but I just can't bear the idea that
我就受不了.
it use to be a cow.
克莉丝:一头牛!!??
Chrissy: A cow!!??
麦琪:宝贝,这块给你.我知道你喜欢吃烤牛肉的.
Maggie: Here you go sweetheart, you have always loved roast beef.
克莉丝:一头牛!!???
Chrissy: A cow!!???
麦琪:凯特,那你就吃点蔬菜吧.
Maggie: Kate, surely you can have some of the vegetables.
凯特:哦,我先洗洗,你不介意吧?
Kate: Oh, do you mind if I wash them off?
麦琪:做菜前,我都洗干净了.
Maggie: I washed them off before I cooked them.
凯特:是的.可这上面全是肉汁.
Kate: Yes, but they were cooked in the meat juice.
麦琪:我不知道肉汁也有头脸.
Maggie: I wasn't aware meat juice had a face.
杰森:呃…那么,餐桌上有你能吃的东西吗?
Jason: Umm...Is there anything at all on the table that you can have?
凯特:这是凉水吗?
Kate: Is this tap water?
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: Yes.
凯特:哦,那么…不要.
Kate: Oh then....No.
克莉丝:猪排是从哪里来的?
Chrissy: So what do pork chops come from?
开萝尔:当然是猪了.
Carol: Well pigs.
克莉丝:那么羊排呢?
Chrissy: And lamb chops are?
本:狗!
Ben: Beah!
克莉丝:啊!!
Chrissy: Ah !!
开萝尔:你怎么一点都不讲究啊,你这个小坏蛋.
Carol: You have absolutely no finesse, you butthead.
凯特:谢谢你们费心费力地张罗这顿饭.
Kate: Well, thank you for going through the trouble and making the food and all.
杰森:啊!
Jason: Aww!
凯特:要是以前的话,我肯定非常喜欢.
Kate: There was a time I would have really enjoyed it.
麦琪:是的,迈克早该告诉我们你这么讲究吃喝.
Maggie: Yes, well Mike should've told us your diet was weird.
哦,不是讲究,只是不吃有脸的食物.
No no, not weird, face free.
凯特:哦,你不该责怪迈克,他最近很忙.
Kate: Well you can't blame mike he's been so busy lately
杰森:是的.他肯定想说的,只是忘记了而已.
Jason: Oh I'm sure he meant to tell us, it just slipped his mind.
麦琪:对,因为一般情况下,他是个很负责的孩子.杰森,麦琪,凯特:我要宰了这家伙.
Maggie: Yeah, cause normally he's the most responsible boy.Jason, Maggie, Kate: I'm going to kill him!!
凯特:哦,晚安.
Kate: Oh good night.
麦琪:是的,晚安,凯特.
Maggie: Yeah, good night Kate.
杰森:凯特,晚安.
Jason: Good night Kate.
凯特:老天啊!这不是可爱的二色藤嘛.
Kate: Oh gosh!That's a lovely variegated philodendron.
麦琪:要我给你热热吗?
Maggie: Would you like me to heat it up for you?
杰森:凯特,你一个城市女孩植物懂的还真不少啊.
Jason: Well Kate for a city girl you know a lot about plants.
凯特:我老家在尤蒂卡,全家都是农民.
Kate: I'm from Utica, my whole family's farmers.
杰森:听到了吗,麦琪?她来自乡下,那是盐城.
Jason: You hear that Maggie, farm people, salt to the ear.
麦琪:肯定含钠量很少.
Maggie: Low sodium, I'm sure.
杰森:我们把凯特送到车上去,好吗?
Jason: Why don't we walk Kate to her car?Shall we?
凯特:今晚太棒了.下次你们到我老家,
Kate: This has been great,
我下厨房.
next time you come to my place and I will cook for you.
麦琪:啊,不久,叶子要落了,秋天要来了.我去拿甜点.
Maggie: Well, the leaves will be falling off the tree soon.I'll bring desert.
克莉丝:巧克力有生命吗?
Chrissy: Was chocolate a life?
开萝尔:没有,亲爱的.
Carol: No, honey.
本:除了复活节的小兔兔.
Ben: Little bunnies at Easter.
克莉丝:啊!!!
Chrissy: Ah!!!
迈克:你就是这么吃饭的吗?先把围裙围上再偷吃好吗!!??
Mike: So this is how you eat!!?You just put on that apron and you steal food!!??
卢克:对,我还是去拿条新围裙吧,玉米牛肉这道菜全是油.
Luke: Yeah but I got to get a new apron cause the corn beef here is really fatty.
迈克:别偷吃了,也别撒谎了,
Mike: No more stealing, no more lies alright!!??
好吗!!??我不会让你这样流落街头的!!
I can't let you live on a street like this!!
卢克:你不会吗?今天早上我没有流落街头,
Luke: Oh you can't let me!!??Well this morning I wasn't on the street.
我有睡的地方,有吃的地方,而且有读书的地方.
I had a place to sleep and a place to eat and a promising academic career.
而现在呢?就因为你,我真成了无家可归,饥寒交迫的人了.你算老几?查尔斯凯丁这样的警察?
Now thanks to you I'm a homeless hungry dropout.Who are you?Charles Keeting!
迈克:我只是想让你过上更好的生活,不再受苦.
Mike: It's just I want a better life for you than the one you've been living.
卢克:这样吗?你有什么好主意吗?
Luke: Is that right?Well you got any suggestions?
迈克:好了,进来吧.
Mike: Alright, come on in.
卢克:你肯定没问题吗?
Luke: Are you sure this is ok?
迈克:是,是,你可以睡在我妹妹的房间里.别担心,没关系的.她一直在学校里住.明天你再跟我爸爸聊聊.
Mike: Yeah yeah, you can sleep in my sister's room.Don't worry it's fine she's away at college and you can talk to my dad in the morning.
卢克:我听你的.
Luke: I don't know.
迈克:别担心,这很好.你上楼去,
Mike: Stop worrying, it's fine just go on upstairs,
右边第一个房间.呃…对了,有时她在床上会放个呃…
first door on the right and uhh... Sometimes she keeps this umm...
大绒毛玩具狗.拿开它,上床就行了.
big stuffed dog on her bed just shove it off and hop in.
卢克:好了,晚安.
Luke: Ok, good night.
迈克:晚安,哦,不!我没赶上晚饭!凯特会杀了我的!
Mike: Good night.Oh no!I missed dinner!Kate's going to kill me!
还好,今晚总算没出别的事情.开萝尔:啊!!!00:22:18,600
Well at least nothing else can go wrong tonight. Carol: Ah!!!!